Guide to the Robert B. Fisher Photograph Collection and Papers WA MSS S-2823
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Glass Transparencies and Lantern Slides, circa 1850-circa 1921; Series III; 9.1; 11 boxes
  - Lantern Slides by Identified Photographers
    Transparent positive images made or mounted on glass that measure 3.25 to 3.5 by 4 inches.
    - Barley, H. C. (Box 15, Folder 530-531)
    - Brooks, Harry Ellington (Box 15, Folder 532)
    - Case and Draper Photographers (Box 15, Folder 533)
    - Church Army (Box 15, Folder 534-537)
    - Dobbs, Beverly Bennett (Box 15, Folder 538)
    - Eaton, W. A. (Box 15, Folder 539-545)
    - Gifford, Benjamin A. (Box 15, Folder 546)
    - Great Northern Railway (Box 15, Folder 547)
    - Haynes St. Paul (Box 15, Folder 548-549)
    - Hegg, E. A. (Box 15, Folder 550)
    - Hughes, W. C. (Box 15, Folder 551-552)
    - Jackson, William Henry (Box 15, Folder 553-555)
    - Keystone View Co. (Box 15, Folder 556-558)
    - Levy, Isaac Georges (Box 15, Folder 559-568)
    - Levy Ses Fils (Box 15, Folder 569-571)
    - McNally (Box 15, Folder 572)
    - Miles Brothers (Box 15, Folder 573)
    - Newton and Co. (Box 16, Folder 574-601)
    - Reyes, J. (Box 16, Folder 602)
    - Rodolph, F. B. (Box 16, Folder 603-604)
    - Smith Hassell Co. (Box 16, Folder 605-606)
    - T. H. McAllister (Box 16, Folder 607-613)
    - Tibbetts, H. C. (Box 16, Folder 614)
    - Underwood and Underwood (Box 16, Folder 615)
    - United States Reclamation Service (Box 16, Folder 616)
    - Waters, R. J. (Box 16, Folder 617-620)
    - Wyatt, Ralph Judson, circa 1921 (Box 17, Folder 621-673)
    - Wyatt, Ralph Judson, circa 1921 (Box 18, Folder 674-716)
    - York and Son (Box 16, Folder 717-726)
  - Lantern Slides by Unidentified Photographers
    - Locations in the United States
      - Alaska (Box 19, Folder 727-748)
        - Eskimos (Box 19, Folder 749-756)
      - Arizona (Box 19, Folder 757-761)
      - California (Box 19, Folder 762-787)
        - San Francisco (Box 20, Folder 788-802)
        - Yosemite (Box 20, Folder 803-811)
      - Colorado (Box 20, Folder 812-815)
      - Louisiana (Box 20, Folder 816)
      - Maine (Box 20, Folder 817)
      - New Hampshire (Box 20, Folder 818-819)
      - New Mexico (Box 20, Folder 820)
      - North Dakota (Box 20, Folder 821)
      - Wyoming (Box 20, Folder 822-823)
      - United States Geological Survey (Box 20, Folder 824-828)
    - Locations Outside the United States
      - Alps (Box 20, Folder 829)
      - Australian Photographers (Box 20, Folder 830-831)
      - Denmark (Box 20, Folder 832)
      - Egypt (Box 20, Folder 833-835)
      - France (Box 20, Folder 836-838)
      - India (Box 20, Folder 839)
      - Italy (Box 21, Folder 840-847)
      - Japan (Box 21, Folder 848)
      - Norway (Box 21, Folder 849)
      - Switzerland (Box 21, Folder 850)
      - Turkestan (Box 21, Folder 851-852)
      - Turkey (Box 21, Folder 853)
    - United Kingdom (Box 21, Folder 854-856)
      - Cathedrals (Box 21, Folder 857-861)
        Collodion lantern slides
      - London (Box 21, Folder 862-868)
    - Topics
      - Animals (Box 21, Folder 869-872)
      - Astronomy (Box 21, Folder 873-875)
      - Aviation History (Box 22, Folder 876-903)
      - [Empty folders due to numbering errors during processing the collection] (Box 22, Folder 904-905)
      - Horse racing (Box 22, Folder 906)
      - Mining (Box 22, Folder 907-909)
      - Philippine American War (Box 22, Folder 910-924)
      - [Empty folders due to numbering errors during processing the collection] (Box 22, Folder 925-929)
      - Portraits (Box 22, Folder 930-933)
      - Unidentified landscapes and interiors (Box 22, Folder 934-938)
    - Non-photographic Subjects
      - Advertisements (Box 22, Folder 939-944)
      - Art by Elsie Anna Wood (Box 23, Folder 945-946)
      - Biblical scenes (Box 23, Folder 947)
        - Prodigal Son (Box 23, Folder 948-951)
        - Stations of the Cross (Box 23, Folder 952-953)
      - Hawaii (Box 23, Folder 954-959)
      - Paris, France (Box 23, Folder 960-964)
      - Venice, Italy (Box 23, Folder 965-967)
- Copy Photographs, circa 1990-circa 1997; Series IV; 1.3; 1 box
  Series IV is organized into two subseries: Mounted Copy Photographs and Unmounted Copy Photographs.
  This subseries chiefly consists of copy photographs of material in the Fisher collection. The negatives for the photographs accompany many of the photographic prints.
  Individual titles and dates of copy photographs were not captured during processing the collection.
  - Mounted Copy Photographs
    Copy photographs of material in the Fisher collection, which Fisher mounted on boards
    - Daguerreotypes, early American, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 968-976)
    - Daguerreotype stereographs and tintype stereographs, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 977-980)
    - Salted paper print stereographs, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 981-987)
    - Glass stereographs, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 988-1007)
    - Tissue stereographs and photomechanical stereographs, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1008-1010)
  - Unmounted Copy Photographs
    Copy photographs of material in the Fisher collection, as well as related photographs and texts, which are grouped together by format and subject
    - Daguerreotypes, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1011)
      Copy photographs of daguerreotypes in the collection of Leonard Olarsch, Short Hills, New Jersey
    - Salted paper print stereographs, circa 1991 (Box 24, Folder 1012)
    - Glass stereographs, circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1013-1021)
    - Stereographs, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1022-1025)
    - Non-photographic stereographs, circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1026)
    - Pannotypes, circa 1990 (Box 24, Folder 1027)
    - Cartes de visite, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1028)
    - Lantern slides, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1029-1046)
    - United States Geological Survey photographers, circa 1990-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1047)
- Printed Material, 1842-1932; Series V; 1; 1 box
  Series V is organized into 5 subseries: Subjects in the United States, Subjects Not in the United States, Portraits, Photography, and Gigantism.
  This subseries chiefly consists of illustrated articles, tear sheets, and prints with illustrations that Fisher compiled chiefly as resources for identifying photographic images.
  - Subjects in the United States
    - United States, General
      - Bain, H. Foster. "Our National Survey: The Romance of Scientific Pioneering." The Booklovers Magazine 3.2 (1904): 201-216., 1904 February; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1048)
      - Eggleston, Edward. "Church and Meeting-House Before the Revolution." The Century. 33.6 (1887): 901-912., 1887 April (Box 25, Folder 1049)
      - Hart, Albert Bushnell. "Some of the New Englanders Who Helped Build Up the Great West." Munsey's Magazine. 38.2 (1907):139-150., 1907 November (Box 25, Folder 1050)
      - Hill, Robert T. "Running the Cañons of the Rio Grande." The Century. 61:3 (1901): 371-387., 1901 January (Box 25, Folder 1051)
      - "Mountain and Shore: Typical Summer Playgrounds of America." The Booklovers Magazine. 4.1 (1904): 75-86., 1904 July (Box 25, Folder 1052)
    - California (Box 25)
      - Brooks, Noah. "Bret Harte in California." The Century. 58.3 (1899): 447-451., 1899 July (Box 25, Folder 1053)
      - Stoddard, Charles Warren. "In Old Bohemia: Memories of San Francisco in the Sixties." The Pacific Monthly. 6.18 (1907): 638-650., 1907 December (Box 25, Folder 1054)
    - Connecticut
      - Howland, Edward. "An Industrial Experiment at South Manchester" Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 45.270 (1872): 836-844., 1872 November (Box 25, Folder 1055)
      - Lamb, Martha Joanna. "Lyme: A Chapter of American Genealogy." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 52.309 (1876): 313-328., 1876 February (Box 25, Folder 1056)
      - Lathrop, George Parsons. "A Model State Capital." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 71.425 (1885 ): 715-734, 1885 October (Box 25, Folder 1057)
    - Maryland
      - Casson, Herbert. "Baltimore, The Metropolis of the South - Its Romantic History and Its Strategic Position." Munsey's Magazine. 39.3 (1908): 295-317., 1908 June (Box 25, Folder 1058)
    - Massachusetts
      - Brayley, Arthur. "The Churches of Boston Fifty Years Ago. The Bostonian. 2.4 (1895): 346-378., 1895 July (Box 25, Folder 1059)
    - Minnesota
      - Powell, L.W. "The Land of Lakes; or, The New Northwest." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 51.35 (1875): 624-641., 1875 October (Box 25, Folder 1060)
        Lacks page 641
    - New Hampshire
      - Drake, Samuel Adams. "The White Mountains (Part 2)" Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 43.3743 (1881): 190-212., 1881 June-July (Box 25, Folder 1061)
      - Rideing, William Henry. "White Mountains." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 40.327 (1877): 321-332., 1877 August (Box 25, Folder 1062)
    - New York
      - Blackshaw, Randall. "The New New York." The Century Magazine. 64.4 (1902): 493-513., 1902 August (Box 25, Folder 1063)
      - Carroll, Charles. "New York in Summer." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 57.341 (1878): 689-704., 1878 October (Box 25, Folder 1064)
      - Coburn, Alvin Langdon. "Some Photographic Impressions of New York." The Metropolitan Magazine. 23.5 (1906): 537-544., 1906 February (Box 25, Folder 1065)
      - "Collection of Historic Engravings." Journal of American History. 3.4 (1909): 575-576, 579-580 (Box 25, Folder 1066)
      - Duer, Elizabeth. "New York Society a Generation Ago." Harper's Monthly Magazine. 105.625 (1902): 109-114., 1902 June (Box 25, Folder 1067)
      - Dwight, Harrison Griswold. "An Impressionist's New York." Scribner's Magazine. 38.5 (1905): 544-554., 1905 November (Box 25, Folder 1068)
        Missing pages 544, 553-554
      - Ford, James L. "The Flash Age of New York." Appleton's Magazine. 10.5 (1907): 574-583., 1907 November (Box 25, Folder 1069)
      - Harper Brothers. "Madison Square, New York. Junction of Broadway and Fifth Avenue. Fifth Avenue Hotel on the Left", 1878; (2 newspaper clippings) (Box 25, Folder 1070)
      - Harriman, Florence Jaffray. "Hither and Yon (Part 1)." The Century Magazine. (1923): 651-665., 1923 September (Box 25, Folder 1071)
      - Harrington, John Walker. "A Little Journey Through the New York Streets." The Puritan. 9.2 (1900): 201-212., 1900 November (Box 25, Folder 1072)
      - Hemstreet, Charles. "Bowling Green: The Oldest Park in the World." The Four-Track News. (1932): 294-296., 1932 October (Box 25, Folder 1073)
      - Hinshalwood, Robert, engraver. "Lake George." Based on a painting by John William Casilear., 1863; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1074)
      - Hinshalwood, Robert, engraver. "The Adirondack Woods." Based on a painting by John McDougal Hart., 1874; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1075)
      - Home, Rufus. "The Story of Tammany (Part 2)." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 44.264 (1872): 835-848., 1872 April-May (Box 25, Folder 1076)
      - Howells, William Dean. "Letters of an Altrurian Traveller (Part 5)" The Cosmopolitan. 16.5 (1894): 558-568., 1894 January-March? (Box 25, Folder 1077)
      - Hunt, Samuel Valentine, engraver. "Long Island Sound." Based on a painting by James Augustus Suydam., circa 1863; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1078)
      - Hunt, Samuel Valentine, engraver. "West Point and the Highlands." Based on a painting by Henry Fenn. Printed by D. Appleton Co., 1869; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1079)
      - Hunt, Samuel Valentine, engraver. "The Catskills. Sunrise from South Mountain." Based on a painting by Henry Fenn. Printed by D. Appleton Co., 1873; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1080)
      - Ingersoll, Ernest. "Reasoning Out Metropolis." St. Nicholas. 25.3 (1898): 196-202., 1898 January (Box 25, Folder 1081)
      - Janvier, Thomas Allibone. "Down Love Lane." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 87.520 (1893): 582-595., 1893 September (Box 25, Folder 1082)
      - Janvier, Thomas Allibone. "The Dutch Founding of New York (Part 3)." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 106.635 (1903): 739-749., 1903 February-April (Box 25, Folder 1083)
      - Kelley, William V. D. "Adding Color to Motion." Transactions of the Society of Motion Picture Engineers. 3.7 (1919): 76-79., 1919 April
      - "Key to the Panoramic View of New York." The Illustrated London News. (1876): 181., 1876 August 19
      - Kimmel Voigt, printers. "View on the Hudson near West Point. Engraved Expressly for Demorest's Magazine .", circa 1880-1890; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1084)
      - Kobbé, Gustav. "The Story of the States, No. 13, New York: The Imperial City of the Western World." Pearson's Magazine. 14.82 (1902): 979-994., 1902 October (Box 25, Folder 1085)
      - Kobbé, Gustav. "The Story of the States, No. 13, New York: The State Which is an Empire." Pearson's Magazine. 14.83 (1902): 1101-1118., 1902 November (Box 25, Folder 1086)
      - Lewis, Henry Harrison. "New York: The Progress of Three Centuries." The Quaker. 7.4 (1900): 415-426., 1900 March (Box 25, Folder 1087)
      - Lienhard, John H. "The Walk Up-Town." Scribner's Magazine 27.1 (1910): 45-59., 1910 January (Box 25, Folder 1088)
        Missing page 44
      - Martin, E.S. "Knickerbocker Days." The Cosmopolitan. 30.2 (1901): 219-228., 1901 January (Box 25, Folder 1089)
      - Mortimer, James. "A View of New York." The Strand Magazine. 12.70 (1896): 523-528., 1896 November (Box 25, Folder 1090)
      - "New York - A Never Finished City." The Review of Reviews. (1929): 49-52., 1929 September (Box 25, Folder 1091)
      - "New York a Hundred Years Ago." Munsey's Magazine. 40.2 (1908) 196-205., 1908 November (Box 25, Folder 1092)
      - Rhodes, Harrison. "New York - City of Romance." Harper's Monthly Magazine. 119.714 (1909): 914-925., 1909 November (Box 25, Folder 1093)
      - Rideing, William Henry. "Life on Broadway." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 56 (1878): 229-240., 1878 January (Box 25, Folder 1094)
      - Riggs, Edward G., et al. "Wall Street." Epoch. 10.4 (1894): 351-392., 1894 January (Box 25, Folder 1095)
      - Smillie, James, engraver. "Catskill Mountain House." Based on a drawing by George Harvey, 1850; (1 engraving) (Box 25, Folder 1096)
      - "Snapshots of Upper Broadway from Thirty-Fourth Street to Central Park." The New York Times-Illustrated Magazine. (1899): 3.
      - "The Story of the Hudson: New York Harbor." The Mentor. 5.12 (1917): frontispiece. (Box 25, Folder 1097)
      - Van Rensselaer, Mariana Griswold. "Picturesque, New York." The Century Magazine. 45.2 (1892): 164-175., 1892 December; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1098)
      - Van Rensselaer, Mariana Griswold. "Places in New York." The Century Magazine. 53.4 (1897): 501-516., 1897 February; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1099)
      - Wellstood, G. W., engraver. "Mouth of the Moodna, on the Hudson." Based on a painting by David Johnson., 1870; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1100)
      - Wellstood, William, engraver. "City of Buffalo." Based on a drawing by Asa Coolidge Warren., 1855; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1101)
      - Wellstood, William, and Henry Peters, engravers. "Buffalo." Based on a drawing by John William Hill., 1855; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1102)
    - Niagara Falls
      - Dollar, George. "Foolhardy Feats: I. The Niagara Fools." The Strand Magazine. 14.81 (1897): 332-336., 1897 September (Box 25, Folder 1103)
      - Dunlap, Orrin E. "Niagara - The Scene of Perilous Feats." Cosmopolitan. 32 (1902): 358-370., 1902 February (Box 25, Folder 1104)
      - Hulbert, Archer Butler. "The Migration of Niagara Falls." The Four Track News. 10.4 (1906): 297-300., 1906 April (Box 25, Folder 1105)
    - Pennsylvania
      - Bailey, Vernon Howe. "American Cities in Pencil: I. Philadelphia." Everybody's Magazine. 10.2 (1904): 173-179, 1904 February (Box 25, Folder 1106)
      - "Chestnut Street, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania" from James W. Shepp and Daniel B. Shepp. Shepp's Photographs of the World: Consisting of Photographic Views of Cities-Street Scenes-Public Buildings (Boston, Massachusetts: G.V. Jones Company, 1891), 517. (Box 25, Folder 1107)
      - Davis, Rebecca Harding. "Old Philadelphia." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 52.311 (1876): 868-882., 1876 April (Box 25, Folder 1108)
      - Ritter, John P. "Bethlehem." Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly. 47.6 (1899): 596-608., 1899 April (Box 25, Folder 1109)
      - Tatum, George B. "The Origins of Fairmount Park." Antiques. 82 (1962): 500, 502-507., 1962 November (Box 25, Folder 1110)
      - Wellstood, William, engraver. "Philadelphia." Based on a drawing by John William Hill and Benjamin Franklin Smith, 1855; (1 engraving, clipped) (Box 25, Folder 1111)
      - Williams, Churchill. "Philadelphia in Fiction." The Bookman. 16.4 (1902): 360-375., 1902 December (Box 25, Folder 1112)
    - Virginia
      - Cooke, John Esten. "The White Sulpher Springs." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 57.339 (1878): 337-356., 1878 August (Box 25, Folder 1113)
    - Washington, D.C.
      - Hunt, Gaillard, ed. "Washington in the Hands of the British: From the Diaries and Family Letters of Mrs. Samuel Harrison Smith (Margaret Bayard)." Scribner's Magazine. 39.4 (1906): 425-444., 1906 October (Box 25, Folder 1114)
      - Hunt, Gaillard, ed. "Washington in Jackson's Time with Glimpses of Henry Clay: From the Diaries and Family Letters of Mrs. Samuel Harrison Smith (Margaret Bayard)." Scribner's Magazine. 39.5 (1906): 608-626., 1906 November (Box 25, Folder 1115)
      - Orr, Lyndon. "The Most Brilliant Days of Old-Time Washington Society." Munsey's Magazine. 38.6 (1908): 709-719., 1908 March (Box 25, Folder 1116)
      - Roberts, D. E., "Early Days at the National Capital." National Magazine. 13.5 (1901): 371-377., 1901 February) (Box 25, Folder 1117)
      - Swayne, Wager. "The Site of the National Capital." Harper's New Monthly Magazine 40.236 (1870): 181-192., 1870 January (Box 25, Folder 1118)
      - Townsend, George Alfred. "New Washington." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 50.297 (1875): 306-322., 1875 February (Box 25, Folder 1119)
  - Subjects Not in the United States
    - Austria-Hungary
      - Browne, Junius Henri. "Down the Danube (Concluded)." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 45.269 (1872): 817-835., 1872 October-November (Box 25, Folder 1120)
      - Browne, Junius Henri. "Along the Elbe." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 46.274 (1873): 495-508., 1873 March (Box 25, Folder 1121)
      - Browne, Junius Henri. "The Principalities of the Danube." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 52.310 (1876): 474-486., 1876 March (Box 25, Folder 1122)
      - Conway, Moncure Daniel. "Vienna." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 46.276 (1873): 831-852., 1873 May (Box 25, Folder 1123)
      - Davis, J.W., Mrs. "A Glimpse of Prague." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 56.332 (1878): 161-176., 1878 January (Box 25, Folder 1124)
    - Brazil
      - Evans, Thomas C. "A Health Trip to the Tropics. III.–Tijuca and Petropolis." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 39.234 (1869): 625-831., 1869 September-November (Box 25, Folder 1125)
        Two copies of "A Health Trip to Brazil. II.–Rio and Its Environs."
        "A Health Trip to the Tropics. III.–Tijuca and Petropolis." missing page 818
      - Smith, Herbert Huntingdon. "The Mediterranean of America." Scribner's Monthly. 18.2. (1879): 192-204, 1879 June (Box 25, Folder 1126)
      - Smith, Herbert Huntingdon. "Rio de Janeiro." Scribner's Monthly. 18.6. (1879): 192-204, 1879 October (Box 25, Folder 1127)
        Missing page 903
    - Canada
      - Benjamin, Samuel Greene Wheeler. "Prince Edward Island." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 40.328 (1877): 545-554., 1877 September (Box 25, Folder 1128)
    - Cuba
      - Churchill, Winston. "The Battle With Cervera's Fleet Off Santiago." The American Monthly Review of Reviews. 18 (1898): 153-166., 1898 August (Box 25, Folder 1129)
      - Conant, Helen Charlotte Peters Stevens. "Life in Cuba." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 43.255 (1871): 350-364., 1871 August (Box 25, Folder 1130)
      - Höffler. "Circa de las Posas, on the Pan de Guajaybon, Cuba." The Illustrated London News. (1869): 393-394., 1869 October 16
      - Dawley, Thomas Robinson, Jr. "Some Cuban Photographic Sketches." Cosmopolitan. 24.1 (1897): 21-28., 1897 November (Box 25, Folder 1131)
      - Lee, Fitzhugh. "Cuba Under Spanish Rule: Personal Impressions of the Island, People, and Government, and of the War for Freedom." McClure's Magazine. 11.2 (1898): 99-114., 1898 June (Box 25, Folder 1132)
      - "War Time Snap Shots." Munsey's Magazine. 20.1 (1898): 3-32., 1898 October (Box 25, Folder 1133)
    - Egypt
      - Conant, Samuel Stillman. "Ismaïlia." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 50.296 (1875): 233-246., 1875 January (Box 25, Folder 1134)
    - Europe, General
      - Audenreid, Joseph Crain. "General Sherman in Europe and the East (Third Paper)" Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 47.281 (1873): 652-671., 1873 July-October (Box 25, Folder 1135)
        "General Sherman in Europe and the East (Third Paper)" missing page 671
    - France
      - Johnson, Clifton. "Glimpses of Life in France." The Outlook. 61.1 (1899): 47-54, 1899 January 7 (Box 25, Folder 1136)
      - Kidder, F. A. "First View of the Exposition." The Cosmopolitan. 29.3 9 (1900): 227-240., 1900 July (Box 25, Folder 1137)
        Includes frontispiece that depicts a view of the Trocadero and Colonial Section of the Exposition Universelle of 1900 in Paris
      - Shanly, Charles Dawson. "French Exposition for Twenty Cents." Our Young Folks. 4.3 (1868): 170-177, 1868 March (Box 25, Folder 1138)
      - Stanton, Theodore, Alfred Stevens, and Henri Gervex. "The Paris Panorama of the Nineteenth Century." The Century. 39.6 (1889): 256-269., 1889 December (Box 25, Folder 1139)
      - Stead, William T. "The Paris Exposition." The Cosmopolitan. 29.4 (1900): 339-360. (Box 25, Folder 1140)
      - Towne, Charles A. "Plans for the Paris World's Fair." The Cosmopolitan. 28.2 (1899): 149-162., 1899 December (Box 25, Folder 1141)
    - Italy
      - Abbott, Lyman. "The City of the Saints." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 45.266 (1872): 169-186., 1872 July (Box 25, Folder 1142)
      - Abbott, Lyman. "The Eternal City." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 44.259 (1871): 1-19., 1871 December (Box 25, Folder 1143)
      - Morgan, Lewis Henry. "The City of the Sea." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 45.268 (1872): 481-501., 1872 September (Box 25, Folder 1144)
    - Japan
      - Abbott, Lyman. "Pictures of the Japanese." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 39.231 (1869): 305-320., 1869 August; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1145)
      - "Commodore Perry's Expedition to Japan." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 12.70 (1856): 441-466, 1856 March (Box 25, Folder 1146)
      - Griffis, William Elliot. "The Mikado's Empire." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 53.316 (1876): 496-514., 1876 September (Box 25, Folder 1147)
    - Netherlands
      - Browne, Junius Henri. "Holland and the Hollanders (Second Paper)." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 44.261 (1872): 349-364., 1872 January-February (Box 25, Folder 1148)
      - Penfield, Edward. "Amsterdam Impressions." Scribner's Magazine 37.7 (1905): 45-53., 1905 January (Box 25, Folder 1149)
        Missing page 53
      - Penfield, Edward. "Holland from the Stern of a Boeier." Scribner's Magazine 34.76 (1905): 721-728., 1903 December (Box 25, Folder 1150)
    - Panama
      - Pratt, Julius H. "To California by Panama in '49." The Century. 41.6 (1891): 901-917. [photocopy], 1891 April (Box 25, Folder 1151)
    - Scotland
      - Constable, Thomas. "Archibald Constable and his Friends." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 48.286 (1874): 501-512, 1874 March (Box 25, Folder 1152)
    - United Kingdom